麦琪:杰森,你有没有纸巾?给我一张.
Maggie: Oh Jason, don't you have a tissue?For me.
迈克:我还记得你们说我们太草率呢.
Mike: I thought you guys said that Julie and I were rushing into this.
朱莉:你怎么会有这样的想法?
Julie: Where'd you get an idea like that?
牧师:我亲爱的...
Priest: Dearly beloved...
迈克:我愿意.
Mike: I do.
牧师:...我们今天相聚一堂,
Priest: ...we are gathered together today,
来见证朱莉卡斯特洛和迈克尔的婚礼.
to witness the marriage of Julie Lin Costello and Michael Aaron Seaver.
博内尔:真棒!!!
Boner: Yeah!!!
牧师:婚姻是神圣的,而不是儿戏,
Priest: Marriage is an honorable state, and as such,
因此,我恳请在座的每一位,
should not be entered into lightly, so,
如果有人认为他们俩不能结为夫妻,请马上说出你的理由,
if anyone has just cause why this couple should not be wed,
否则,就永远不要说.
speak now or forever hold your peace.
会众:我有话要说!!我有话要说!!
Congregation: I do!!I do!!
牧师:真难办.我想现在只有你们俩能给出一个满意的结婚的理由,
Priest: Tough room.I'm sure these God fearing people would dummy up if
否则这些让上帝也害怕的人恐怕很难停下来了.
you'd give them one good reason why you two are getting married.
会众:( 仍然不停的叫喊,以阻止婚礼的进行)
Congregation: (shouting in protest to the wedding)
朱莉:哦,是呀,我也很好奇哦.
Julie: Well yeah, I'm curious too.
迈克:啊...恩...呃...
Mike: Ah...well...err...
朱莉:迈克!
Julie: Mike!
迈克:呃...呃...(迈克从睡梦中惊醒,嘴里说着)我爱你!我爱你!
Mike: Err...err...(Mike wakes up from his dream) I love you!I love you!
开萝尔:哈!我鸡皮疙瘩都起来啦!
Carol: Ha!You disgust me!
迈克:开萝尔,我不是跟你道过歉了吗?你还想怎么样呢?
Mike: Look Carol, I said I was sorry, alright?
开萝尔:哈!
Carol: Ha!
迈克:开萝尔,我是说像你这样的女孩子,
Mike: Carol, I mean, what guy in their right mind would want to grab you,
还有哪个正常的男孩子会来抱你呢?喂,等等!
anyway?Hey Wait!Carol!I'm sorry, alright?
开萝尔!我不是故意的,我有点神志不清了;我昨天晚上睡的一点也不踏实.
I'm just kind o' spaced out here; I didn't get much sleep last night.
不知道为什么,我一直都在做一个关于我和朱莉的噩梦.
I don't know why, I had this wild dream about me and Julie.
开萝尔:迈克,拜托,
Carol: Mike, please, I just lived that disgusting dream;
我刚刚从你那个恶心的梦中恢复过来;不必再听第二次了.
I don't need to hear about it.
迈克:等等,开萝尔.所有的请帖都写错了.
Mike: Wait a minute, Carol.These invitations are all wrong.
开萝尔:爸妈也是这样说的.
Carol: That's what Mom and Dad have been saying for months.
迈克:哦,不,
Mike: Oh, no, no, no.
不,不.
Look, right here- "as Julie and Mike celebrate the beginning of their
你看,就这里-"庆祝朱莉和迈克开始一起生活.""生活这个单词要用复数."
life together." It should be- "lives together."
我去年在一份英语报纸上,也看见过这样的错误.
Hey, I mean, I got that wrong on an English paper last year.
开萝尔:迈克,我非常佩服你的文学才能,可是你弄漏了一点.
Carol: Mike, I applaud your flash of literacy, but you're missing the point.
你和朱莉开始的是一个共同的生活,一个,知道吗?
You and Julie are starting "a" life together...one life, get it?
迈克:哦,那我们俩谁会失去生活呢?
Mike: Yeah, so which one of us is losing our life?
麦琪:哇,你把所有的请柬都准备好了?
Maggie: Wow, you got all the invitations done.
迈克:妈妈,
Mike: Mom, look, I am not in the mood to hear, one more time,
我已经没有心思再听你说那些让我和朱莉等待的所谓的合理解释了.
all of your sensible reasons why Julie and I should wait.
麦琪:这么说,你也承认我的解释是合理的了?
Maggie: So, you admit, they're sensible reasons?
迈克:妈妈,你根本就不知道我在说什么.
Mike: Mom, you're missing the key idea here.
麦琪:迈克,非常抱歉,你说的有道理.我已经在上个星期承诺过好几次,不会再说任何不赞成的话.从现在开始,我会用最好的精神状态来准备你们的婚礼.
Maggie: Mike, I'm sorry, you're right.Like I promised last week, and several times before that, no more negativity.From this day forward, I'll embrace your marriage with gusto.
迈克:妈妈,你的话听起来像是在为啤酒做宣传.
Mike: Mom, you make it sound like a beer commercial.
麦琪:我要把它办成你一生的婚礼中最好的一次.
Maggie: I just want to make this the best gang wedding you'll ever have.
迈克:妈,这会是我一辈子中仅有的一次婚礼.
Mike: Mom, it's the only "gang" wedding I'll ever have.
麦琪:亲爱的,要不要我帮你贴信封呀?
Maggie: Honey, would you like me to lick your envelopes for you?
迈克:妈妈,你不必如此假惺惺了.
Mike: Mom, look, you don't have to pretend that much.
麦琪:我哪有.
Maggie: Yes I do.
迈克:妈妈,其实...其实我们也有考虑过这件事情.
Mike: Mom, it's...it's not like we haven't thought about this.
麦琪:亲爱的,你不必再想那些了;我能了解你的感受,
Maggie: Honey, you don't have to go through all that again;
因为20年前,我也有这样的感受.
I know how you feel, because twenty years ago, I was you.
而朱莉的处境就和当时你爸爸的一样,我现在的行为和当时我妈妈的一样,而你外公就是...
Your dad was Julie, my mom was me, Grandpa Ed was...
我的天,我怎么越来越像我妈妈了.
Gosh, I'm starting to sound like my mother.
迈克:妈妈,你一点也不像外婆,快继续说下去.你现在越来越接近问题的关键所在了...不是吗?
Mike: No, Mom, Mom, keep going.You were real near making a point...weren't ya?
麦琪:是的.迈克,
Maggie: Yes.Mike, you're not getting married to please us;
我想通了,
you're getting married because this is something you want to do,
你结婚不是为了要取悦我们;你结婚是因为你想要结婚,并且你也很清楚结婚的理由.
and you know all the reasons why.
迈克:是的.我很清楚.
Mike: I do.
麦琪:但是如果你有什么疑问,不要不...
Maggie: But if you have any doubts, don't be too...
迈克:我一点疑问也没有!一点都没有!我对自己信心十足,开心的不得了!
Mike: I have none!I have none!I'm very confident and extremely happy!
麦琪:亲爱的,迈克,
Maggie: And I'm bubbling for you.
我打心眼里为你高兴.对了,要记得去发你的讨厌的请柬.
Mike, honey, don't forget your stinking invitations.
迈克:嗨,爸爸,妈妈有的时候会把我搞的紧张兮兮的.
Mike: Hey Dad, you know sometimes Mom makes me nuts.
杰森:啊,我可从来没说过哦?你说说看.
Jason: Hey, I never said this, OK?Tell me about it.
迈克:呃,我的意思是说妈妈什么时候才会不把我当成小孩子,而当成一个能干,
Mike: Yeah, I mean, when is she finally gonna understand that I am a capable,
稳重的男人呢?我可是马上就要靠自己过活啦.你能借我50块吗?
mature adult, ready to stand on my own two feet.Can I borrow fifty Bucks?
杰森:要钱干嘛?
Jason: For what?
迈克:哦,请柬上要贴邮票.
Mike: Well, for stamps, for the invitations.
杰森:好吧,看在过去的份上.
Jason: Alright, for old time's sake.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
杰森:迈克,我知道你妈妈在烦什么.
Jason: Mike, I know what's upsetting your Mom.
迈克:爸,你看,我可是没有问她要过一分钱.
Mike: Dad, look, I did not ask her for a Dime.
杰森:是,那你记不记得今天星期几呢?
Jason: No, but what day is this?
迈克:星期六呀.
Mike: Saturday.
杰森:你胳膊下面夹的什么东西?
Jason: And what's under your arm?
迈克:汗毛!
Mike: Hair.
杰森:迈克,是你的结婚请柬!你今天要把他们都寄出去的!!
Jason: Mike, it's the wedding invitations!You're mailing them out today!!
迈克:是呀!
Mike: Right!
杰森:在你妈妈看来,这就意味着你永远不会回来了.
Jason: For your mother that represents the point of no return.
迈克:啊,可是我从来没有这样想过.
Mike: Oh, well I never thought of it that way.
杰森:当然,迈克,
Jason: No, no of course you didn't Mike.
你当然不会这样想.因为你自认为对所有的事情都了如指掌.
That's because you've been sure about this thing all along.
对你妈妈来说,她需要一段时间来适应.
For your mom, Mike, well...let's just say it's gonna take her some time.
我呢,我是一直支持你的.
As for me Mike,I'm with you, OK?
因为20年前,我也和你一样.
And that's because twenty years ago, I was you.
你妈妈就和现在的朱莉一样,而你外婆就像你妈妈现在这样,
And your Mom was Julie, and her mom was your mom, and my father was...
而我的父亲...我越来越像你外婆了.
I'm starting to sound like my mother-in-law.
迈克:爸爸,我能问你一些事情吗?
Mike: Hey Dad, look, can I ask you something?
杰森 :当然.
Jason: Mmm.
迈克:恩,那我问啦.
Mike: Well, OK, it's about the wedding...Well see...errm...
是跟婚礼有关的事情...你也知道,呃...
Julie and I have to...to write up our wedding vows, you know and...and...
朱莉和我要写我们的结婚宣言了,我们必须用文字来描述所有的结婚理由,
we have to put into words, all the reasons why we're getting married,
但是有那么多乱七八糟的理由...所以,
and there's just so many of the darn things that...
我想你能不能帮我们简化一下呀.爸爸,我是说,
that I'd like your help in narrowing them down.
你和我们一起写,因为你最擅长简化了.
I mean, Dad, let's face it, you are a dynamite narrow-downer.
杰森:谢谢你的夸奖.好吧,现在让我们来听听你的理由.
Jason: Well thank you.OK.Well let's go over the reasons.
迈克:恩,首先,
Mike: Oh, right, well I love her.And...and...and....
我爱她.然后,然后就和你当初娶妈妈的理由相同了.
err all the same reasons why you married Mom.
杰森:哦,迈克,
Jason: Oh, Mike, Mike, I...
迈克,我...我根本无法想像,
I just couldn't imagine spending another day without her.
如果没有她的话,我该怎么过.从跟她求婚的那一刻直到此时此刻,
I mean from the moment that I proposed, right up until this instant Mike,
我都深信你妈妈是这个世界是,唯一适合我的人.
I've never had any doubt that your mother was the only one for me.
迈克:从来没有动摇过?一次也没有?这是我们的妈妈吗?
Mike: Never a doubt?Not one?This is Mom we're talking about.
杰森:我说的都是真心话!我曾经也和你一样,有过想要放弃的念头,你不要抵赖哦.但是,这个念头并不是怀疑,而是每个人都会有的,是最正常不过的事情了.
Jason: Ah, come on!I had cold feet, just like you're having now, and don't you deny it.But that's...err...not the same as doubt, Mike, that's normal...it's required.
迈克:真是这样的吗?
Mike: Really?
杰森:我敢保证.
Jason: Mmm.
迈克:接着呢,爸爸,你是怎么挺过来呢?
Mike: Well then, what did you do to get over the cold feet?
杰森:每个人的方法都会不一样的哦.是一首歌让我明白了"是在她的脸上吗?
Jason: Oh, it's a little different for everybody.
不,不,
I think for me it was a song- "Is it in her face?
那只是她的外表.是在她的怀抱中吗?不,
Oh, no, that's just her charm.In her warm embrace?No, no, that's just her arm.
不是,那只是她的胳膊.
If you wanna know, if she loves you so, it's in her kiss,
如果你想知道她爱不爱你,可以从她的亲吻中找到答案."
that's where it is.Shoop shoop."
迈克:就是这首歌陪你走过来的?
Mike: And that's what got you through?
杰森:没错,怎么样?楼上,我还留有唱片呢.
Jason: Hey, I got the record upstairs.
迈克:不用了,好了,爸爸,我以后会找来听的!还有一大堆婚礼的事情等着我去准备呢,我要迟到了...嗨,爸爸,听了你的歌后,我觉得我的困惑都消失了.
Mike: No, Dad, it's OK, I'll listen to it later, Ok!I got lots of wedding stuff to do, and I'm late now and...heck Dad, just listening to that song my cold feet are warming right up.
杰森:霍霍.
Jason: Shoop shoop.
朱莉:迈克 ,我真不敢相信...这个是干什么的?
Julie: Mike, I didn't expect you...Gee, what was that for?
迈克:我只是想让你知道,没有你,
Mike: I just want you to know,
我真不知道该怎么活下去.
that I cannot imagine spending another day of my life without you.
朱莉:哦哦.
Julie: Oh.
迈克:从跟你求婚的那天起,
Mike: And I mean that I am as sure of that as I was,
我就一直深信这一点.
the day that I proposed to you.
朱莉:噢.我都不知道要说什么了.
Julie: Well, I don't know what to say.
迈克:你一句话也不必说.让我们就坐在这里,
Mike: You don't have to say anything.
好好的憧憬一下我们的幸福的婚礼...
Let's just sit down right here,
啊?我要走了!
and just be happy about the fact that we are getting married...ahh.Got to go!
朱莉:你怎么了?刚来就要走?那你来干什么呀?
Julie: What do you mean, you gotta go?Why'd you come over?
迈克:哦,哦,想起来了,结婚请柬!
Mike: Oh, oh, right, the invitations!
在我寄出这些请柬前,想让你看看有没有问题.好了,我真的要走了!
I wanted you to look at the invitations before I send 'em out.See!Gotta go!
朱莉:迈克!
Julie: Mike!
迈克:朱莉,还有好多事情等着我去做呢.
Mike: Lots to do, Julie.
我还要去拿我的晚礼服,我会在1点钟去见你和牧师的.
Look, I have to get my tuxedo,
还有,
and I'm meeting you and the minister at one o' clock.
还要去买邮票,贴邮票!
Plus, I gotta get stamps, and lick 'em all by myself.
朱莉:迈克,你真可爱,你是这么的独立,性感和成熟.
Julie: You are so sweet, and so dependable, and so sexy, and so mature.
迈克:哦,信封是开萝尔填的,不是我填的.
Mike: Alright, Carol addressed 'em, I didn't.
朱莉:你走之前,不吻一下我吗?
Julie: Before you go, one last kiss?
迈克:1点钟见.朱莉,
Mike: I'll see you.
我现在担心的不行了,我甚至不知道这是否仅仅只是爸爸所说的恐惧还是其他别的?
Julie, I am scared out of my mind, I mean,
我束手无策了.迈克,
I don't know if this is just cold feet, or what?I am not sure about...
你要真正的变成熟,变成熟!
anything.Real mature, Mike.Real mature.
迈克:哎,我也不喜欢这件.
Mike: Hey, look, I don't like this one either.
裁缝:小伙子,你已经试穿了40件了.这件又有什么问题?
Tailor: You've tried on forty, son.What's wrong with this one?
迈克:我不知道...可能是不喜欢这个翻领吧.
Mike: I don't know...it's the lapels.
裁缝:没问题.分叉怎么样?
Tailor: No problem.How's the crotch?
迈克:可以,可以.
Mike: Fine, fine.
裁缝:小伙子,从长远来看,
Tailor: In the long run, son,
如果你买下这件礼服,而去租妻子,会便宜很多哦.
it'd be cheaper if you'd buy the tuxedo and rent the wife!!
迈克:先生,你结婚了吗?
Mike: Sir, are you married?
裁缝:啦,在过去的56年里,我一直在等待着一个合适的女孩能走进这扇门.
Tailor: Na.For the past fifty six years, I've been waiting for the right gal to walk through that door.
迈克:但是,这不是男人的店吗?
Mike: But, isn't this a men's store?
裁缝:哦,老天啦,我已经浪费了多么好的时光!不,
Tailor: My God, I've wasted my life!No, to tell you the truth, I am married...
老实说,我已经结婚了,45年来都是和同一个女人一起生活.
to the same woman for forty five years.
迈克:那...那你们为什么要结婚呢?
Mike: And...and why did you two get married?
裁缝:性!
Tailor: Sex!
迈克:可是...可是,当性欲消失后呢?
Mike: Well...well what happens when the sex goes away?
裁缝:船到桥头自然直.
Tailor: We'll cross that bridge when we come to it.
迈克:恩,打扰一下,你介意我换一首歌听吗?
Mike: Ah, excuse me, do you mind if I change this song?
裁缝:这首歌有什么不好吗?
Tailor: What have you got against the shoop shoop song?
迈克:说来话长.
Mike: It's a very long story.
裁缝:我来一些皮带出来给你看看.
Tailor: Let me show you some cummerbunds.
收音机:现在是"提问教练"时间,体育迷们,我们已经为大家开通了所有的热线电话,如果你有什么问题,赶快打电话给无所不知的"教练"吧.
Radio: All phone lines are open, sports fans, 'cause it's time for, "Ask the Coach"; the man who knows all the men, with all the answers.
迈克:提问教练?
Mike: Ask the Coach?
收音机:是的,这里是提问教练.
Radio: That's right!Ask the Coach.
教练:是谁这么不识趣的来打扰我的美梦?最好给我一个合理而漂亮的理由!!
Coach: Whoever the hell is calling me on my one and only stinking day
你好.
to sleep late?Better have a pretty good, dandy reason!!Hello.
接线员:是你以前的得意门生的电话.好,
Operator: Collect call from your favourite former student.
好,马上就接进来.
Oh, sure, sure, put him on!
迈克:啊哈,教练!
Mike: Yo!Coach!
教练:若比,你现在混的怎么样?
Coach: Robby Countryman, so how are you doing?
迈克:啊,不,不是,教练,我不是若比,我...我是迈克.
Mike: Oh, no, coach, it's not Robby, it's...it's Mike.
教练:你姓什么?
Coach: Mike who?
迈克: 迈克斯威.
Mike: Mike Seaver.
教练:那你是我以前的得意门生吗?
Coach: My favourite former student?
迈克:你还记不记得,在中学的时候,
Mike: Remember back in high school, you said that if I ever had a problem,
你跟我说过,如果我遇见任何的问题,都可以跟你说?
I could talk to you?
教练:不记得了.但是你可以接着说,不过得快点,因为我要付电话费.
Coach: No.But go ahead anyway.But make it fast, this is my Nickel.
迈克:好的,好的.我...我...我刚刚订婚,我的未婚妻是个出色的女人.但是,我却不知道我现在的所作所为是否正确.
Mike: OK, alright, well see...I...I...I'm engaged now and my fiancé is the greatest.But it's just that, I still don't know if what I'm doing is the right thing.
教练:我说过了,不要吞吞吐吐的.
Coach: I said, fast.
迈克:人结婚是为了什么呢?
Mike: Why do people get married?
教练:为什么?要不然,你让他们去干什么呢?
Coach: Why?well, what the hell else are they gonna do?
迈克:我不明白你的意思.
Mike: What do you mean?
教练:西维尔,你想想看,你是个男人.我想你的未婚妻肯定是个女人.
Coach: Look, Seaver, you're a man.I'm assuming your fiancé is a woman.
你们相遇,接着就结婚,对你,对我,对所有人都一样.
You meet, you get married, for you, for me, for everybody.
迈克:可是,教练,我还是不明白.
Mike: Oh well coach, I don't understand.
教练:没关系,因为我们现在正在讨论爱情的谜底.
Coach: Well that's because we're talking about the mystery of love here.
迈克:那,谜底到底是什么呢?
Mike: Well, what's that?
教练: 傻瓜!如果我知道的话,那还能叫谜吗?
Coach: If I knew, it wouldn't be a mystery, lug nut!
迈克:哦,这么说来,你也不懂了?
Mike: Oh, so you don't understand it either?
教练:我没必要去搞懂它,只要经历过就好了.
Coach: I don't have to understand it, I'm living it.
听着,
Look, Seaver, isn't there somebody else you could talk to about this...
西维尔,难道在你那个区就没有人可以和你讨论这件事情吗?
in your own area code?
迈克:恩,我想没有.
Mike: Yeah, I guess.
教练:我要上床去睡觉了.
Coach: I'm gonna go back to bed.
假如你还想和我再谈谈这件事情,
And if you ever, ever, ever call me about something like this again...
我随时恭候.
I'll be here.
迈克:谢谢你,教练.
Mike: Thanks coach.
教练:下次别再让我付电话费了.
Coach: Just don't make it collect.
迈克:好的.再见.他们会知道的.
Mike: Alright.See ya.They'll know.
外公:迈克!
Grandpa: Mike!
外婆:好啊,迈克!
Grandma: Hi Mikey!!
迈克:外婆好!
Mike: Hi Grandma!
外婆:看见你真好!
Grandma: So glad to see you!
外公:你一个人来的?你爸爸没来吗?
Grandpa: Your father isn't with you, is he?
迈克:我一个人来的.
Mike: No.
外公:见到你真开心.
Grandpa: Good to see you.
迈克:谢谢.我刚刚经过这里,所以就顺道来看看你们.
Mike: Thanks.Yeah, I thought that...err...the heckers!!As long as I was in your lobby I might as well come up and say hi.
外婆:哦,你什么时候都能给我惊喜.
Grandma: Well, you can surprise me, anytime.
外公:哦,你外婆一直这样说我的呢.
Grandpa: Oh, that's what your grandmother tells me too.
外婆:鲍比!
Grandma: Oh Bobby!
迈克:恩,我...呃...我就是想来看看你们俩在干什么.
Mike: Yeah, I...errm...just wanted to see how you two love birds were doing.
外婆:呵,我们本来打算要长羽毛的呢...你要和我们一起吗?
Grandma: Well, we were just going to have our...errm...fiber.Care to join us?
迈克:好啦,好啦,给我一个铲子吧.
Mike: Ah...sure, sure, heck, give me a scoop.
外婆:干什么?
Grandma: What's the matter?
迈克:没什么.没什么,
Mike: Nothing.Nothing, Grandma.Nothing's the matter.Julie's...err...
外婆.朱莉已经拿到她的礼服了,我也马上要去拿我的了,
got her gown, and I've almost got my tuxedo, and...err...
我们...我们约好今天去教堂见牧师.
we're meeting the minister today at the church...
外婆:迈克尔!
Grandma: Michael!
外公:你现在是不是想反悔了,迈克?
Grandpa: Are you...err...having second thoughts, Mike?
迈克:没有!那我们现在是要谈谈婚礼的事情还是谈长羽毛的事情呢?好了,如果你们答应替我保密,我就告诉你们,行不行?
Mike: No!Now look, are we gonna talk about this or are we gonna have some fibre?Alright, if I tell you guys something, can you keep it a secret?
外公:你绝对可以相信我.你看,
Grandpa: You can trust me.
我从来没跟其他人提起过你外婆的胎记.
I've never told anybody about your grandmother's tattoo.
外婆:天啦,威利!
Grandma: Oh Wally!
外婆:是呀,我都没有告诉他你的胎记在哪里呢.
Grandpa: Yes, but I didn't tell him where it is.
外婆:亲爱的,不要听你外公瞎说!
Grandma: Ignore him honey!
迈克:恩.你们俩结婚的理由是什么?
Mike: OK.What was the reason that you two got married?
外婆:哦,当你知道你爱上一个人的时侯,你就可以结婚了,还需要什么别的理由吗?
Grandma: Oh, when you love somebody and you know it, what else do you need?
迈克:但是,你怎么知道你爱上了那个人呢?
Mike: Yeah, but how can you know that?
外婆:怎么可能会不知道呢?
Grandma: How can you not?
迈克开始回想
(in Mike's head)
教练:你们相遇,然后结婚,这就是整个过程.
Coach: You meet, you get married, that's how it works.
开萝尔:你和朱莉开始的只是一个生活,一个.
Carol: You and Julie are starting "a" life together...one life.
麦琪:你要结婚,只是你想要结婚,
Maggie: You're getting married because this is what you wanna do,
你也都明白为什么要结婚.
and you know all the reasons why.
杰森:是在她的脸上吗?不,
Jason: Is it in her face?No, no, that's just her charm.In her warm embrace?
不,那只是她的外表.是在她的怀抱中吗?
No, no, no, that's just her arm.
不,不是,那只是她的胳膊.
If you wanna know, if she loves you so, it's in her kiss,
如果你想知道她爱不爱你,可以从她的亲吻中找到答案.
that's where it is.Shoop shoop.
酒保:说说俱乐部里年龄最大的人是谁?
Bar Tender: The oldest man ever to play in the Major Leagues?
客人1:迷尼曼露斯.
Customer 1: Minnie Mannose.
酒保:错.
Bar Tender: Wrong.
客人2:塞尔吉奥佩琪.
Customer 2: Sergio Page.
客人1:我来问你一个问题;赢得联盟最后一个三冠王的是谁?
Customer 1: I got one for you Nick; the last man in the National League,
to win the Triple Crown?
客人2:周多科梅德维克, 圣.路易斯,1937年.
Customer 2: Joe Dockey Medwick, St.Louis, Nineteen hundred and thirty seven.
客人1:不错,伙计!
Customer 1: Hey, you're good pal!
客人2:你可以随便问.
Customer 2: Ask me anything.
迈克:人结婚是为了什么?
Mike: Why do people get married?
酒保:喂,伙计,我们正在讨论体育呢.
Bar Tender: Look son, we're talking sports.
客人2:嘿,婚姻也是一种运动哦.
Customer 2: Hey, marriage can be a sport.
客人1:没错,婚姻是接触运动,哈哈!
Customer 1: Yeah!A contact sport!
迈克:不,不,我是认真的!
Mike: Well, no, no, I'm serious!
我说,我基本上已经问过所有我认识的人,
I mean, I've asked basically everyone that I know,
可是呢,他们说的那些都没有什么新鲜的,都是我自己也明白的.
and all I can come up with is, that I know as much as anybody else.
客人2:那就是说,你都弄明白了啦.
Customer 2: Then kid, you know it all.
酒保:他怎么可能完全明白呢?他不过是个小毛孩而已.
Bar Tender: How can he know it all?He's only a kid.
客人1:那你知道什么呢,小毛孩?
Customer 1: What do you know, kid?
迈克:我清楚的知道朱莉是爱我的.
Mike: Well, I know that Julie loves me.
客人1:哦,这是最基本的.我是说,如果你要和朱莉结婚的话.
Customer 1: Well, that's a start.I mean, if it's Julie you're gonna marry.
酒保:等等,等等!如果那个女孩想要和他结婚,那他就得结了吗?
Bar Tender: Wait, wait, wait, wait!If this girl wants to marry him, that...that makes the marriage right?
迈克:没错,她一般都不会错的.
Mike: Well, she's usually right.
酒保:你确定?
Bar Tender: Are you sure?
迈克:恩,在我的印象中,
Mike: Look, I can't ever remember her being wrong.
她从来没有做错什么.并且,她比我机灵多了.
I mean, Julie is smarter than me.
她知道的事情也比我多的多,可以肯定的说她比我更成熟.
And she knows more than me, and she is definitely more mature than me.
客人2:男人都需要成熟的女人.
Customer 2: A man needs a mature woman.
迈克:如果朱莉都没有丝毫的怀疑,那...
Mike: If Julie doesn't have any doubts, then...what am I worried about?
我有什么好不安的呢?对,我要娶她!
I am going to marry Julie.
酒保:你确定?
Bar Tender: Are you sure?
迈克:我长这么大,还从来没有像现在这样对一件事情这么肯定.说真的,
Mike: I have never been more sure about anything in my entire life.
我都不知道该怎么来感谢你们,帮我理出头绪.
Look, I can't thank you guys enough for helping me put all this together.
谢谢,非常感谢!我要去见我未来的妻子了.
Thanks.I am going to meet my future wife.
迈克:我是新郎,骑着...
Mike: Here comes the groom, riding the...
妇女:我能为你做点什么吗?
Woman: Can I help you?
迈克:恩,我正需要你的帮助呢.我叫迈克尔西维尔,我和我未婚妻约好一点钟在这里见牧师的.
Mike: Ah, yes, I'm sorry.My name's Michael Seaver, and my fiancé and I are
meeting the minister here at one o' clock
妇女:西维尔先生,哦,有件东西是留给你的.
Woman: Mr.Seaver, yes.Well, this was left for you.
迈克:哦,谢谢.
Mike: Oh, well thank you.
(迈克在他的大脑里开始读信,那是朱莉留给他的.)
(Mike reads the letter in his head, from Julie.)
朱莉:亲爱的迈克,当你看这封信的时候,也许我已经在飞机上了.
Julie: Dear Mike, by the time you read this, I'll be on a plane.
这是我第一次写这样的信,所以,
I have never written a letter like this before, so I don't know how to start.
都不知道该如何下笔.最近,我不停的想着我和你,
I've been thinking about you and me and marriage, and,
还有我们的婚姻,我知道一直以来,你都认为我比你成熟,
well I know you think that all the time I've been the mature and the sure
比你有把握.但是,
one.But I have to say, that when it comes to us,
我不得不承认,当我们真的准备要结婚的时候,你显得比我要成熟.
you've been the mature one.
迈克:我更成熟?
Mike: I've been the mature one?
(他继续读下去)
(He continues reading from the letter)
朱莉:你不要不承认.我真的很想知道,你怎么会知道那么多.迈克,而我,却有无数的问题和怀疑.我想也许是我不对劲,或者我只是太害怕.我真的不知道,也许只是一时的恐惧.我唯一清楚的就是,自己实在已经不能坚持下去了.你今天早上来看我的时候,我就想告诉你,但是,你让我怎么有勇气开口呢?你看上去是那么的信心满满,还带着所有的请柬.当我终于下定决心跑出去找你的时候,而你,早已经走远了.我知道,对你来说一定很难理解这些困惑.
Julie: Don't deny it.I just want to know, how you can know so much.Mike, I've got so many questions, and I've got so many doubts.And maybe I'm crazy, or just scared out of my mind.I just don't know, maybe it's just cold feet.But all I know right now, is that I can't go through with this.And I wanted to tell you all this morning when you came by, but how could I?I mean you looked so determined with all those invitations under your arm.Well, by the time I got up my courage, I ran out to the hall way and you were already gone.And look, I know my confusion must be hard for you to understand.
迈克:我能理解.
Mike: It's not that hard.
朱莉的信:迈克,真是很抱歉.我多么希望自己能像你一样...但是,
Julie's letter: Mike, I'm sorry.I wished I could be more like you...
我不能.所以,迈克,好好保重.深爱你的朱莉.
but I'm not.So, take care of yourself.Love Julie.
(迈克开始回忆)
(In Mike's memory)
朱莉:你走之前,能不能最后吻我一次?
Julie: Before you go, one last kiss?
迈克:呆会儿见.
Mike: See ya.
朱莉:再见.
Julie: Bye.
迈克:朱莉,我很害怕,
Mike: Julie, I'm scared out of my mind,
我不知道这只是一时的恐惧还是其他别的什么?
I don't know if this is just cold feet, or what?I am not sure about...
对所有的事情,我都没有把握.
anything.
迈克:我觉得我是捡了个便宜.
Mike: Well, I'd say I got a bargain.
博内尔:依我看,你根本就是迷失自己.
Boner: And I'd say, you've lost your mind.
迈克:据说这里住着一个人.
Mike: It says, a man lives here.
博内尔:迈克,如果它再说废话,你就开枪.
Boner: Mike, well if it says anything, shoot it.
迈克:知道了,好,就这里,抓紧我.可以了吗?
Mike: Alright, well here, hold my moose.Alright, got it?
博内尔:行了.迈克,你没事吧?
迈克:我生龙活虎呢.
00:21:29,000
Boner: Yep.Yo, Mikey, are you alive, or what? Mike: Alive and kicking.